In the last video, we saw a first method to request messages received under the LoRaWAN server.
This method is interesting because it's very simple.
Whenever we need to get the uplink message, then we just ask for it.
But if we analyze it closer, we can see a few drawbacks.
The first drawback is that we only worked on the uplink stream.
There is no possibility to send a downlink message to the LoRaWAN server with this kind of request.
Why?
Simply because no LoRaWAN server has implemented the possibility to ask to the user, the downlink message to
send to the device.
It doesn't really matter because we'll see other methods to do so.
But we have to keep in mind that with HTTP GET request, we can only get the uplink message from the
server, but we can't send downlink message to it.
The second drawback is that for the uplink stream, we spend our time requesting data that potentially
doesn't exist.
We request data without knowing if it has been received.
So, for example, if a sensor is sending, let's say a few times a day, then we'll have to make periodic
requests with a high chance of receiving empty responses.
That's definitely not efficient because it increases unnecessarily the network load.
So if this HTTP GET request is so bad, then you could ask why does it exist?
Actually, if for some reasons on our IoT platform, we've had a problem during a certain time, then
we will be very happy to know that these data are still on the LoRaWAN server for a few hours and
we can get them with the HTTP GET request.
So what can we do to improve the data transmission between the LoRaWAN server and the IoT platform?
From the IoT platform side, instead of asking for data.
Then, it would be a much better idea to receive them whenever they are available.
It's possible and very simple.
We just need to reorganize the client and server rules.
And now the client Pushes the message to the server.
It's possible because the request is not a GET request anymore, but a POST request.
That's what we're going to explain in the next video.